<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The second set of madrigales to 3. 4. 5. and 6. parts apt for viols and voyces. Newly composed by Thomas Bateson, Bacheler of Musicke, organist, and master of the children of the cathedrall church of the blessed Trinitie, Dublin, in the realme of Ireland.</title>
            <title>Madrigals. Set 2</title>
            <author>Bateson, Thomas.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1618</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 102 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 62 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A72612</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 1587</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S123069</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99900310</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99900310</idno>
            <idno type="VID">150784</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A72612)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 150784)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1980:14)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The second set of madrigales to 3. 4. 5. and 6. parts apt for viols and voyces. Newly composed by Thomas Bateson, Bacheler of Musicke, organist, and master of the children of the cathedrall church of the blessed Trinitie, Dublin, in the realme of Ireland.</title>
                  <title>Madrigals. Set 2</title>
                  <author>Bateson, Thomas.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[158] p. : music  </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>printed by Thomas Snodham, for Matthew Lownes and Iohn Browne,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1618.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Six partbooks, each with separate dated title page and register. At head of title, part 1, "Cantus."; part 2, "Altus"; part 3, "Tenor"; part 4, "Bassus"; part 5, "Quintus"; part 6, "Sextus". At foot of titles: Cum priuilegio.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: [A]²  B-E⁴ (-E4); [A]²  B-E⁴ (-E4); [A]²  B-D⁴; [A]²  B-E⁴ (-E4); [A]²  B-C⁴ D² (-D2); A⁴.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the Bodleian Library, Oxford, England.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Madrigals, English --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-01</date>
            <label>Susie Lorand</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <group>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <front>
               <div type="title_page">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:1"/>
                  <p>ALTVS.</p>
                  <p>THE SECOND SET <hi>OF</hi> MADRIGALES to 3. 4. 5. and 6. Parts: Apt for Viols and Voyces.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>NEWLY COMPOSED</hi> by Thomas Bateſon, Bacheler of MVSICKE, Organiſt, and Maſter of the Children of the Cathedrall Church <hi>of the bleſſed</hi> TRINITIE, <hi>Dublin, in</hi> the Realme of IRELAND.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed by <hi>Thomas Snodham,</hi> for <hi>Matthew Lownes</hi> and <hi>Iohn Browne.</hi> 1618.</p>
                  <floatingText type="license" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Cum Priuilegio.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </div>
               <div type="illustration">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:2"/>
                  <p>
                     <figure>
                        <figDesc>coat of arms of Arthur, Lord Chichester, Baron of Belfast</figDesc>
                        <head>HONOR SEQVITVR FVGIENTEM</head>
                     </figure>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="dedication">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:2"/>
                  <head>TO THE RIGHT HONO<hi rend="sup">rable,</hi> 
                     <hi>ARTHVRE</hi> Lord <hi>CHICHESTER,</hi> Baron of BELFAST, Lord high Treaſurer of <hi>Jreland,</hi> and one of his Majeſties moſt Honorable Priuy Counſell, of that KINGDOME.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Right Honorable:</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">B</seg>Eing to expoſe theſe my vnworthy Labours to publicke view, and vniuerſall cenſure, I was imboldened in a double reſpect to become ſo humbly-ambitious, as to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire that they may take ſanctuary vnder your Honors all-pleaſing name and ſafeſt patronage; Firſt, becauſe they were ſolely entended for your Honors priuate re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creation, after your tedious imployments in the af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fayres of the common-wealth, being then his Maieſties moſt worthy Deputy, and ſwaying the ſword and ſcep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of authority amongſt vs, in this kingdome of <hi>Ireland;</hi> And as your Honour hath beene pleaſed to vouchſafe vnto them your priuate applauſe, and thereby to occaſion me for more variety to enlarge them to this number: So I am bolde to father them vpon your Honor, not doubting but as in your allowance of them, I made vſe of your goodneſſe, ſo in your protection of them, I may make vſe of your greatneſſe. Secondly, it is not the leaſt of your Honors fauours conferred vpon me, to grace me with your Honourable ſeruice, and to call me to a more immediate dependency vpon your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, and therefore to auoide the blacke note of ingratitude, I held it my duty there to lay downe my worke, where I owe my ſeruice, and to deſire to be no longer knowne, then I may be knowne with that relation I haue to your Honour; that ſo I might leaue a perpetuall teſtimony vnto the world of your Honours fauours vnto mee; of my affectionate deſire, in ſome weake meaſure, to expreſſe my thankefulneſſe to your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour. If I haue herein giuen content to theſe curious and hard-pleaſed times, the thankes belongs to your Honour, whoſe encouragements were my motiues with gree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dineſſe to vndertake this taske, with conſtancy to goe through it, with reſolution to publiſh it, to the cenſorious eare of the world. If I haue come ſhort of popular expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, my hope is, that my mention of your Honorable name will procure pardon for a greater offence. And thus wiſhing vnto your Honor a continuall Harmony, compoſed of a comfortable delight of body, goods, and good name, with a daily increaſe of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, I humbly take leaue, crauing pardon for this boldneſſe, and deſiring alwaies to be accounted</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your Honours to be commanded in the beſt of his ſeruices THOMAS BATESON.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
               <div type="table_of_contents">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:3"/>
                  <head>THE TABLE.</head>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>3.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LOue is the fire that burnes me. I</item>
                     <item>My Miſtris after ſeruice due. II</item>
                     <item>One woman ſcarce of twenty. III</item>
                     <item>If I ſeeke to inioy. IIII</item>
                     <item>Pleaſure is a wanton thing. V</item>
                     <item>Sweet, thoſe trammels of your haire. VI</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>4.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LIue not poore bloome. VII</item>
                     <item>The Nightingale in ſilent night. VIII</item>
                     <item>Oh, what is ſhe? IX</item>
                     <item>See, ſee, forth her eyes her. X</item>
                     <item>When to the gloomy woods. XI</item>
                     <item>If floods of teares. XII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>5.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>HAue I found her? XIII</item>
                     <item>Downe the hills. XIIII</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Camella</hi> faire tript. XV</item>
                     <item>Sadneſſe fit downe. XVI</item>
                     <item>Life of my life. XVII</item>
                     <item>I heard a noiſe. XVIII</item>
                     <item>With bitter ſighes. XIX</item>
                     <item>Why doe I dying liue? XX</item>
                     <item>In depth of greife. XXI</item>
                     <item>All the day, I waſt in weeping. XXII</item>
                     <item>Why doeſt thou flye? XXIII</item>
                     <item>Come ſorrow. XXIIII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>6.</hi> Voices.</head>
                     <item>
                        <hi>CVpid</hi> in a bed of Roſes. XXV</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Cytherea</hi> ſmiling ſaid. XXVI</item>
                     <item>Her haire, the net of. XXVII</item>
                     <item>Fond loue is blinde. XXVIII</item>
                     <item>Ah <hi>Cupid</hi> grant that I. XXIX</item>
                     <item>She with a cruell frowne, XXX</item>
                  </list>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </front>
            <body>
               <div n="alto" type="partbook">
                  <div n="1" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:3"/>
                     <head>I.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">L</seg>Oue is the fire that burnes me, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> loue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> The ſmoakes are thoughts con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſed, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Which dimmes my ſoule, my ſoule, which dimmes my ſoule, And hath my ſence abuſ╌ed, Though fire to aſhes turne me, Yet doth the ſmoke more grieue mee, more, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That dimmes my minde, whoſe light ſhould ſtill relieue me. That dims my minde, whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> relieue me, whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> though fire to aſhes turne me, Yet doth the ſmoke more grieue me, more, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That dims my minde, whoſe light ſhould ſtill relieue me. That dims my minde, whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> relieue me. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="2" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:4"/>
                     <head>II.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">M</seg>Y Miſtriſſe after ſeruice due, Demaunded if indeed my loue were true, I ſaid it was, Then ſhee replide, That I muſt hate whom ſhe defide, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And ſo my ſelfe, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> aboue the reſt, aboue the reſt, Whom ſhe, ſhe ſwore did moſt of all de╌teſt, whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In ſooth ſaid I, you ſee I hate my ſelfe, you ſee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Who ſets my loue on ſuch a peeuiſh elfe. Who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> on ſuch a pee╌uiſh elfe. In ſooth ſaid I, you ſee I hate my ſelfe, you ſee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> who ſets my loue on ſuch a peeuiſh elfe. who ſets <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> on ſuch a pee╌uiſh elfe.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="3" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:4"/>
                     <head>III.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>ONe woman ſcarce of twenty, But hath of teares great plenty, but hath <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Which they powre out like fountaines, That runne downe from the mountaines, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Yet all is but beguiling, Their teares and eke their ſmi╌ling, their <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſmi╌ling, Ile therefore neuer truſt them, Ile <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Since nature hath ſo curſt them, ſince <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That they can weepe in ſmi╌ling, Poore fooles thereby beguil╌ing. poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> beguil╌ing. Ile therefore neuer truſt them, Ile <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Since nature hath ſo curſt them, ſince <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That they can weepe in ſmil╌ing, Poore fooles thereby beguil╌ing. poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> beguil╌ing.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="4" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:5"/>
                     <head>IIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>IF I ſeeke to inioy, If <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the fruits of my paine, of my paine, She careles denyes me, She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with endles diſ╌daine, Yet ſo much I loue her, that nothing can either remoue me, or moue her, Alas, why Contend I, why ſtriue I in vaine? why <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the water to mingle With Oyle that is Ayre, and loues to be ſingle, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Tis not loue but Fate whoſe doome I a╌bide, You pow'rs and you plannets which Deſtenies guide, Change your Oppoſition, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> It fits heau'nly powers to be mild of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition. to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Change your oppoſition, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> It fits heau'nly powers to be milde of Condition. to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="5" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:5"/>
                     <head>V.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">P</seg>Leaſure, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> is a wanton thing, When old and young doe dance and ſpring, doe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pleaſure, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> is a wanton thing, When old and young, when old and young doe dance and ſpring, doe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pleaſure <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pleaſure it is that moſt de╌ſire, de╌ſire, And yet tis but a fooles hire. tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> a fooles hire. Pleaſure it is that moſt de╌ſire, de╌ſire, And yet tis but a fooles hire. tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> a fooles hire.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="6" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:6"/>
                     <head>VI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Weet, thoſe Trammels of your haire, Golden locks more truely are, My thoughts locking to your beautie, Thus you doe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my captiue minde, From my dying body binde, From <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Onely to you, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to doe du╌ty. O my deere let it goe free, Or my body take to thee, Or <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> take to thee, Or <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So your Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiue you ſhall che╌riſh, You ſhall che╌riſh, For if parted thus they lye, Or my thoughts or I muſt dye, Or <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> muſt dye, Or <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> T'will grieue thee, t'will grieue thee, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> grieue thee, if either pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſh, if either pe╌riſh. if either pe╌riſh.</p>
                     <trailer>Here endeth the Songs of Three parts.</trailer>
                  </div>
                  <div n="7" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:6"/>
                     <head>VII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">L</seg>Iue not poore bloome, poore bloome, but periſh, Whoſe Spring froſty Winter blaſteth, Other buds freſh Mayes doe cheriſh, Hyems o're thee his ſnow caſteth, And in wither'd armes thee graſpeth, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Tyrants, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> nothing worſe you can, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> you can, Now my liuely bodies yoaked, is yoaked to the dead corps of a man, Thus with loathed burden choked, thus <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Lingering death with teares inuo╌ked. Lingering death with teares inuo╌ked. lingering <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Lingering death with teares inuoked.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="8" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:7"/>
                     <head>VIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He Nightingale in ſilent night, Doth ſing as well as in the light, doth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> doth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> doth, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> To lull loues watchfull eyes a╌ſleepe, She doth ſuch nightly ſonnets keepe, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſuch <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Hey hoe, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Sing we with all, What fortune vs ſo ere be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fall. what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> befall. vs befall. Hey hoe, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Sing we with all, With fortune vs ſo ere befall. what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> befall. vs befall.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="9" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:7"/>
                     <head>IX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. Firſt part. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">O</seg>H, what is ſhe, what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Oh <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whoſe lookes like light╌nings pierce thus ſuddenly my breſt, thus <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Scorching no skinne? Scorching no skinne? Yet oh yet oh, my heart burnes with a fire fierce, The flames aſcending, aſcending the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> in my face are ſeene, are ſeene, Yet courage man, yet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Her ſpeaking eye doth ſhew, Some fire remaines, from whence thoſe lightnings flew. thoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſome <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="10" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:8"/>
                     <head>X.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. Second part. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Ee, ſee, ſee, ſee, ſee, ſee, ſee, ſee, forth her eyes her ſtartled ſpirit peepes, Which now ſhe on me, which <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> which <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſtraight ſhe off me keepes, ſtraight <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Not able long, lookt off, lookt on, doth bluſh, doth tremble, Sweet wretch ſhe would, but can╌not loue diſſem╌ble, ſweet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſweet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Happy euent, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whats lingering is but ſleight, whats <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> is but ſleight, Who euer lou'd that lou'd not at firſt ſight? at firſt ſight? at <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="11" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:8"/>
                     <head>XI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>WHen to the gloomy woods, to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> When to the barren plain, to the barren plaine, When to the ſtony rocks and ſul╌len floods, I wayling often goe, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and of my Loue complaine, How ſenceles then thinke I, how <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> by loue I grow, To ſenceleſſe things that tell my woe? to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that tell my woe? Yet theſe my piercing moanes, my piercing moanes, yet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my piercing moanes haue touched oft ſo nye, haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oft ſo nye, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That they to me replie, reply, reply, reply, reply, reply, But cruell, cruel, cruel ſhe, More ſenceles then hard ſtones, Quite ſenceles of my paines, No anſwer giues, Vnmoued ſtill remaines. Vnmo╌ued <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Vnmo╌ued <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="12" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:9"/>
                     <head>XII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>F floods of teares. </p>
                     <trailer>Here endeth the Songs of foure Parts.</trailer>
                  </div>
                  <div n="13" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:9"/>
                     <head>XIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Aue I found her? <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> O rich finding, haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> O rich finding, Goddeſſe like for to behold, for to behould, Her faire treſſes, her <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſeemely bind╌ing, In a chaine of pearle and gould, In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of pearle and gould, Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me O moſt faire, Chaine me to thee with that haire, Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with that haire. Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me, O moſt faire, chaine me to thee with that haire. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="14" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:10"/>
                     <head>XIIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>DOwne the hills <hi>Corina</hi> trips, <hi>Corina</hi> trips, <hi>Corina</hi> trips, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Fetching many wan╌ton ſkips, To the groues ſhe doth goe, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Where thouſand birds in a rowe, Sitting all vpon a tree, Came two by two, Then three by three, <hi>Corina</hi> coueting to ſee, to ſee, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, to ſee, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, Tuning notes, Tuning notes of her praiſe, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Doe welcome her with roun╌delayes. with rounde roundelayes. with rounde rounde roundelayes. with rounde rounde roundelayes. rounde roundelayes. Tuning notes of her praiſe, tuning <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Doe welcome her with roun╌delayes, with rounde roun╌delayes. with roun╌de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>layes. with rounde roundelayes, with rounde roundelayes. roundelayes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="15" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:10"/>
                     <head>XV.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Amella</hi> faire tript or'e the plaine, <hi>Camella</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tript <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I follow'd quickly after, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Haue ouertaken her, haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I would faine, and kiſt her when I caught her, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I caught her. But hope be'ng paſt her to obtaine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, I call, She anſwerd me with great diſdaine, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I will not kiſſe at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe at all, I will not, kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I will not kiſſe at all. But hope be'ng paſt her to obtaine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, I call, She anſwerd me with great diſdaine, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I will not kiſſe at all. I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I wil not, I wil not, I wil not kis at all.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="16" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:11"/>
                     <head>XVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Adneſſe ſit downe, ſadneſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> on my ſoule feed, on <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Teare vp thoughts, tombe, a numbed heart, tombe a numbed heart, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tombe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> make wounds to ſpeake, and ſcarres to bleede, On withe╌red ſtrings tune ſpringing ſmart, on <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And leaue this farwell, this farwell, for poſteritie, Life is a death where ſorrow cannot dye. life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> life. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And leaue this farwell for poſteritie, Life is a death where ſorrow cannot dye. life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> life. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="17" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:11"/>
                     <head>XVII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>LIfe of my life, how ſhould I liue alas, a╌las, ſince thou art thus re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolu'd for to depart? for <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Or how ſhould I diſguiſe my ſecret ſmart, Wanting the ſweet fru'tion of thy face? Wanting the ſweet fru'tion of thy face, of thy face, Wher beauty, loue, with maieſtie and grace, Things ſeld or neuer, things <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> things <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> meeting in one place, Haue all conſpir'd to plague a plagued hart, all alwaies careles of my carefull caſe, all <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then if thou wilt not haue thy loue to mourn, to mourne, Goe not at all, goe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> or elſe with ſpeed returne, Nay ra╌ther far my deer goe not away, But thou muſt goe, But <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then ſweet while I thee ſee, Farwel, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But bide, or let me dye. but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="18" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:12"/>
                     <head>XVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>I Heard a noiſe, and wiſhed for a ſight, I lookt aſide, and did a ſhadow ſee, a ſhadow ſee, Whoſe ſubſtance was the ſum of my delight, It came vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeene, and ſo it went from me, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> from me, But yet Conceit perſwaded my entent, There was a ſubſtance where the ſhadow went, the ſhadow went, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I did not play <hi>Narciſſus</hi> in conceit, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I did not ſee my ſhadow in a ſpring, I knew my eyes were dim'd with no deceit, I ſaw the ſhadow of ſome worthy thing, For as I ſaw the ſhadow paſsing by, I had a glance of ſomthing in my eie, Shadow or ſhe, or both, or chuſe you whether, Bleſt be the thing that brought the ſhadow hether. Bleſt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Bleſt be the thing that brought, that brought the ſhadow hether.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="19" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:12"/>
                     <head>XIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Ith bitter ſighs I heard <hi>Amintas</hi> playning, For his chaſt loue, he found but deepe diſdaining, for <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> but deepe diſdai╌ning. As thus he ſat, he ſat, and in his griefe did tremble, To cheere his ſpirits the Aer'all queere aſ╌ſemble, aſſemble, They ſweetly ſing, they <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In dolefull tunes he cryes, Griefes are long li'ud, and ſorrow ſeldome dyes. and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſorrow ſeldome dyes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="20" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:13"/>
                     <head>XX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doe I dying liue, and ſee my life bereft me? and ſee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> bereft me? Why doe I doubt to dye, to dye, and ſee death onely left me? left me, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Th'en largement of my better ſelfe by natures foe, Confines my hapleſſe life, to neuer dying woe, Immur'd in ſorrowes hold I onely ſee the light, of all my ioyes, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Wrapt vp in horrors blackeſt night, wrapt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wrapt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then like Meander Swans, before my death, my death, in fatall notes, Ile ſigh my lateſt breath. Ile <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my lateſt breath.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="21" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:13"/>
                     <head>XXI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N depth of griefe, and ſorrow great, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſorrow great, Oft haue I, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my ſelfe bewailed, my <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of that ſame loue, of that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that late had ſeate in my heart, in my heart, but now is fai╌led, And ſorrow thou haſt done the worſt, That thou canſt doe, to make me curſt, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And ſorrow thou haſt done the worſt, That thou canſt doe, to make me curſt. that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="22" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:14"/>
                     <head>XXII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. Firſt part. LATVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Ll the day, all the day, I waſt in wee╌ping, grieued with, grieued with, my loues, grieued <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> diſdai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, All the night, all the night, I lye complaining, ſighes and ſobs, ſighes <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſighes <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſighes <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> me watchfull keeping, For thy loſſe my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, and now too cruell. once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> once. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> too cruell. For thy loſſe, my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, And now too cruell, once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="23" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:14"/>
                     <head>XXIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. Second Part. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doeſt thou flye? why <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> why <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> in ſuch diſdaine, Stay, or I dye with endleſſe paine, ſtay <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pittie, pittie, pittie my plaint; a ╌las I faint, vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>happy me, wilt neuer be? wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and ſee, thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> thy louer dye.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="24" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:15"/>
                     <head>XXIIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ome ſorrow, helpe me to lament, For plaining. now muſt eaſe my heart, for plaining now, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> No pleaſure can giue me content, content, For all delights doth breede my ſmart, for <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Onely my loue, my loue can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my griefe all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe. my griefe. Onely my loue, my loue, can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my griefe. all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe. my griefe.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="25" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:15"/>
                     <head>XXV.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Firſt part. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>
                           <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pid</hi> in a bed of Roſes, in <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> in <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> in <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſleep╌ing, Sleep╌ing, chanced to be ſtung, of a Bee that lay among the flowers, Where he himſelfe repoſes, Where <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> repoſes, And thus to his mother weeping told, That he this wound did take, this <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Of a little winged ſnake. As he lay ſecurely ſleeping, as <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſecurely ſleeping, And thus to his mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther weeping told, weeping told, That he this wound did take, of a little winged ſnake, As he lay ſecurely ſleep╌ing. as <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> as <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="26" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:16"/>
                     <head>XXVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second Part. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ythe╌rea</hi> ſmi╌ling ſaid, ſmiling ſaid, That if ſo great ſorrow ſpring, ſo <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> From a ſilly Bees weake ſting, From <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> as ſhould make thee thus diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maid, as <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> What anguiſh feele they thinkſt thou, and what paine, Whom thy empoyſ'ned arrows cauſe complaine? whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cauſe complaine? What anguiſh feele they think'ſt thou, and what paine, Whom thy empoyſ'ned arrowes cauſe complaine? Whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> complaine? whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="27" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:16"/>
                     <head>XXVII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Er haire, the net of goul╌den wire, Wherin my heart, Wherein my heart, Led by my wandring eye, led <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So faſt entangled is, entang╌led is, That in no wiſe it can or will againe re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tire, it <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> againe retire it <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tire, againe retire, But rather will in that ſweet bondage die, Then break one haire to gaine her liber╌ty, then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then breake <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> her <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But ra╌ther will in that ſweet bondage dye, Then breake one haire, to gaine her liber╌ty. Then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> her <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="28" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:17"/>
                     <head>XXVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Firſt part. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Ond loue is blind, Blinde therefore louers be, Blinde <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But I more blinde, Who neare my loue did ſee, my loue did ſee, did ſee, <hi>Pigmal'on</hi> lou'd an Image, I a name, I laught at him, But now de╌ſerue like blame, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> like blame, Thus fooliſhly I leape before I looke, Seeing no baite I ſwallowed haue the hooke. Seeing <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus fooliſhly I leape be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I looke, Seeing no baite, I ſwallowed haue the hooke. Seeing no baite, I ſwallow'd haue the hooke.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="29" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:17"/>
                     <head>XXIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second part. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>H <hi>Cupid,</hi> grant that I may neuer ſee, Her through mine eare, that thus hath wounded me, Hir <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> If through mine eyes another wound ſhe giue, <hi>Cupid</hi> alas, <hi>Cupid</hi> alas, then I no longer liue, then I no longer liue, But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharpe arrowes, She ſtole from thy quiuer. She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharpe arrowes, She ſtole from thy quiuer. She ſtole from thy quiuer. She ſtole from thy quiuer.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="30" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:18"/>
                     <head>XXX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. ALTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>He with a cruell frowne, a <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oppreſt my trembling heart with deadly ſwone, with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Yet pitt'ing my paine, yet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Reſtor'd with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe, my life againe, Reſtor'd with a kiſſe, my life againe, Reſtor'd <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with a kiſſe my life, my life againe, Thus let me daily be of life depriued, So I be daily thus againe reui╌ued. So <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I be daily thus a╌gaine reui╌ued. Thus let me daily be of life depriued, of life depri╌ued, So I be daily thus againe reui╌ued, ſo I be <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <front>
               <div type="title_page">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:19"/>
                  <p>TENOR.</p>
                  <p>THE SECOND SET <hi>OF</hi> MADRIGALES to 3. 4. 5. and 6. Parts: Apt for Viols and Voyces.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>NEWLY COMPOSED</hi> by Thomas Bateſon, Bacheler of MVSICKE, Organiſt, and Maſter of the Children of the Cathedrall Church <hi>of the bleſſed</hi> TRINITIE, <hi>Dublin, in</hi> the Realme of IRELAND.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed by <hi>Thomas Snodham,</hi> for <hi>Matthew Lownes</hi> and <hi>Iohn Browne.</hi> 1618.</p>
                  <floatingText type="license" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Cum Priuilegio.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </div>
               <div type="illustration">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:20"/>
                  <p>
                     <figure>
                        <figDesc>coat of arms of Arthur, Lord Chichester, Baron of Belfast</figDesc>
                        <head>HONOR SEQVITVR FVGIENTEM</head>
                     </figure>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="dedication">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:20"/>
                  <head>TO THE RIGHT HONO<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="5 letters">
                        <desc>•••••</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                     <hi>ARTHVRE</hi> Lord <hi>CHICHESTER,</hi> Baron of BELFAST, Lord high Treaſurer of <hi>Jreland,</hi> and one of his Majeſties moſt Honorable Priuy Counſell, of that KINGDOME.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Right Honorable:</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">B</seg>Eing to expoſe theſe my vnworthy Labours to publicke view, and vniuerſall cenſure, I was imboldened in a double reſpect to become ſo humbly ambitious, as to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire that they may take ſanctuary vnder your Honors all pleaſing name and ſafeſt patronage; Firſt, becauſe they were ſolely entended for your Honors priuate re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creation, after your tedious imployments in the af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fayres of the common-wealth, being then his Maieſties moſt worthy Deputy, and ſwaying the ſword and ſcep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of authority amongſt vs, in this kingdome of <hi>Ireland;</hi> And as your Honour hath beene pleaſed to vouchſafe vnto them your priuate applauſe, and thereby to occaſion me for more variety to enlarge them to this number: So I am bolde to father them vpon your Honor, not doubting but as in your allowance of them, I made vſe of your goodneſſe<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> ſo in your protection of them, I may make vſe of your greatneſſe. Secondly, it is not the leaſt of your Honors fauours conferred vpon me, to grace me with your Honourable ſeruice, and to call me to a more immediate dependency vpon your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, and therefore to auoide the blacke note of ingratitude, I held it my duty there to lay downe my worke, where I owe my ſeruice, and to deſire to be no longer knowne, then I may be knowne with that relation I haue to your Honour; that ſo I might leaue a perpetuall teſtimony vnto the world of your Honours fauours vnto mee; of my affectionate deſire, in ſome weake meaſure, to expreſſe my thankefulneſſe to your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour. If I haue herein giuen content to theſe curious and hard-pleaſed times, the thankes belongs to your Honour, whoſe encouragements were my motiues with gree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dineſſe to vndertake this taske, with conſtancy to goe through it, with reſolution to publiſh it to the cenſorious eare of the world. If I haue come ſhort of popular expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, my hope is, that my mention of your Honorable name will procure pardon for a greater offence. And thus wiſhing vnto your Honor a continuall Harmony, compoſed of a comfortable delight of body, goods, and good name, with a daily increaſe of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, I humbly take leaue, crauing pardon for this boldneſſe, and deſiring alwaies to be accounted</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your Honours to be commanded in the beſt of his ſeruices THOMAS BATESON.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
               <div type="table_of_contents">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:21"/>
                  <head>THE TABLE.</head>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>3.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LOue is the fire that burnes me. I</item>
                     <item>My Miſtris after ſeruice due. II</item>
                     <item>One woman ſcarce of twenty. III</item>
                     <item>If I ſeeke to inioy. IIII</item>
                     <item>Pleaſure is a wanton thing. V</item>
                     <item>Sweet, thoſe trammels of your haire. VI</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>4.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LIue not poore bloome. VII</item>
                     <item>The Nightingale in ſilent night. VIII</item>
                     <item>Oh, what is ſhe? IX</item>
                     <item>See, ſee, forth her eyes her. X</item>
                     <item>When to the gloomy woods. XI</item>
                     <item>If floods of teares. XII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>5.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>HAue I found her? XIII</item>
                     <item>Downe the hills. XIIII</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Camella</hi> faire tript. XV</item>
                     <item>Sadneſſe ſit downe. XVI</item>
                     <item>Life of my life. XVII</item>
                     <item>I heard a noiſe. XVIII</item>
                     <item>With bitter ſighes. XIX</item>
                     <item>Why doe I dying liue? XX</item>
                     <item>In depth of greife. XXI</item>
                     <item>All the day, I waſt in weeping. XXII</item>
                     <item>Why doeſt thou flye? XXIII</item>
                     <item>Come ſorrow. XXIIII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>6.</hi> Voices.</head>
                     <item>
                        <hi>CVpid</hi> in a bed of Roſes. XXV</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Cytherea</hi> ſmiling ſaid. XXVI</item>
                     <item>Her haire, the net of. XXVII</item>
                     <item>Fond loue is blinde. XXVIII</item>
                     <item>Ah <hi>Cupid</hi> grant that I. XXIX</item>
                     <item>She with a cruell frowne, XXX</item>
                  </list>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </front>
            <body>
               <div n="tenor" type="partbook">
                  <div n="7" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:21"/>
                     <head>VII.</head>
                     <opener>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap> TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">L</seg>Iue not poore bloome, liue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> but periſh, Whoſe Spring froſty Winter blaſteth, Other buds freſh Mayes doe cheriſh, Hyems o're thee his ſnow caſteth, And in wither'd armes thee graſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>petrh, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Tyrants, Tyrants, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> nothing worſe you can, nothing you can, Now my liuely body's yoaked, is yoaked to the dead corps of a man, Thus with loathed burden choked, thus <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Lingering death with teares inuoked. Lingering <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="8" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:22" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>VIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He Nightingale in ſilent night, Doth ſing as well as in the light, as <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> doth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> as in <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> doth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the light, To lull loues watchfull eyes aſleepe, She doth ſuch nightly ſonnets keepe, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſuch Hey hoe, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Sing we with all, What for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tune vs ſo ere befall. ſo ere be╌fall. what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to vs be╌fall. Hey hoe, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Sing we with all, What fortune vs ſo ere befall. ſo ere be╌fall, what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to vs be╌fall.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="9" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:22"/>
                     <head>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </head>
                     <opener>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="4 words">
                           <desc>〈◊◊◊◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> part. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">O</seg>H, what is ſhe, what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Oh what is ſhe, Whoſe lookes like lightnings pierce thus ſuddenly my heart, thus <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Scorching no skinne? Scorching <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Yet oh, yet oh yet oh my heart burnes with a fire fierce, The flames aſcending, aſcen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> in my face are ſeene, in <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Yet courage man, yet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Her ſpeaking eye doth ſhew, Some fire remaines, ſome <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſome fire remaines, From whence thoſe lightnings flew, ſome <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="10" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:23" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>X.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. Second part. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Ee, ſee, ſee forth her eyes her ſtartled ſpirit peepes, Which now ſhe on me, which <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> which <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſtraight ſhe off me keepes, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Not able long, lookes off, lookes on, doth bluſh, doth tremble, Sweet wretch ſhe would, ſweet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſweet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> but cannot loue, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> diſſemble, ſweet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> loue diſ╌ſemble, Happy euent, Happy e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uent, Whats lingering is but ſleight, Whats <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> is but ſleight, Who euer lou'd that lou'd not at firſt ſight? at firſt ſight? who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that lou'd not at firſt ſight?</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="11" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:23" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>WHen to the gloomie woods, When to the barren plaine, when <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> When to the ſtony rocks and ſullen, ſullen floods, I way╌ling of╌ten goe, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> often goe, How ſenceles then thinke I, how, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> By loue I grow, To ſenceles things that tell my woe? to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that tell my woe? Yet theſe my piercing moanes, my piercing moanes, my, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my piercing moanes, Haue touched oft ſo nye, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oft ſo nye, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That they to me re╌plie, to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But cruell ſhe, but cru╌ell ſhe, More ſenceleſſe then hard ſtones, then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Quite ſenceles of my paine, No anſwere giues, Vnmoued ſtill re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maines, vnmoued <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Vnmoued ſtill remaines.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="12" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:24" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4 Voc. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>F floods of teares, &amp;c.</p>
                     <trailer>Here endeth the Songs of foure Parts.</trailer>
                  </div>
                  <div n="13" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:24" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Aue I found her? O rich finding, haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> O rich finding, Goddeſſe like for to behold, for <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Her faire treſſes ſeemely bind╌ing, In a chaire of pearle and gould, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of pearle and gould, In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of pearle and gould, Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me O moſt faire, Chaine me to thee with that haire, Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me, O moſt faire, Chaine me to thee with that haire. Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me to thee with that haire.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="14" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:25"/>
                     <head>XIIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>DOwne the hills <hi>Corina</hi> trips, <hi>Corina</hi> trips, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Fetching many wanton ſkips, To the groue ſhe doth goe, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Where thouſand birds in a rowe, Sitting all vpon a tree, vpon a tree, And three by three, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <hi>Corina</hi> coueting to ſee, to ſee, to ſee, to ſee, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, <hi>Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, Tuning notes of her praiſe, of her praiſe, Tuning <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with Rounde╌layes. with rounde roundelayes, with rounde roundelayes. roundelayes. with rounde rounde roundelayes. with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Tuning notes of her praiſe, of her praiſe, Tuning <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with rounde layes, with rounde rounde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>layes. with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> roundelayes. with rounde rounde roundelayes, with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="15" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:25"/>
                     <head>XV.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Amella</hi> faire tript or'e the plaine, tript <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tript <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I follow'd quickly after, Haue ouertaken her, I would faine, haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and kiſt her when I caught her, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> when <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But hope be'ng paſt her to ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, She anſwerd me with great diſdaine, I will not kiſſe at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe not kiſſe, not kiſſe at all. But hope be'ng paſt her to obtaine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, She anſwerd me with great diſdaine, I will not kiſſe at all. I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe, not kiſſe, not kiſſe at all.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="16" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:26"/>
                     <head>XVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Adneſſe ſit downe, ſit downe, on my ſoule feed, on my ſoule feede, Teare vp thoughts, tombe a numbed heart, a numbed hert, tombe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> a numbed heart, Make wounds to ſpeake, and ſkarres to bleede, On withered ſtrings tune ſpringing ſmart, tune ſpringing ſmart, And leaue this farwell for poſteritie, (O)life is a death where ſorrow cannot dye. life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> life. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cannot dye, where <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And leaue this farwell, for poſteritie, (O) Life is a death, wher ſorrow cannot dye, Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> can<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>not dye. where <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="17" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:26" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XVII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">L</seg>Ife of my: Or how ſhould I diſguiſe, or how ſhould I diſguiſe my ſecret ſmart, my ſecret ſmart, Wanting the ſweet fru'tion of thy face, of thy face, Wanting <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Where beauty, loue, with maieſtie and grace, and grace, with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Things ſeld or neuer, things <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> meeting in one place, Haue all conſpir'd to plague a pla╌gued hart, to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> All alwaies careles of my carefull caſe, Deere to my ſoule, Deere <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I pray thee make no ſtay, Goe not at all, goe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> or elſe with ſpeed returne, Nay rather far my deere goe not away, goe not a╌way, But thou muſt goe, Then ſweet while I thee ſee, Farwell, farwell, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> farwell, But bide or let me dye, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="18" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:27" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>I Heard a noiſe, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and wiſhed for a ſight, a ſight, I lookt aſide, and did a ſhadow ſee, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whoſe ſubſtance was the ſumme of my delight, It came vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeene, it <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> vnſeene, and ſo it went from me, from me, But yet Conceit perſwaded my entent, There was a ſubſtance where the ſhadow went, there <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I did not play <hi>Narciſſus</hi> in conceit, conceit, I did not ſee my ſhadow in a ſpring, I knew my eyes were dim'd with no deceit, I ſaw the ſhadow of ſome worthy thing, For as I ſaw the ſhadow paſsing by, I had a glance of ſomthing in my eye, I had a glance of ſomething in my eie, Shadow or ſhe, or both, or chuſe you whether, Bleſt be the thing that brought the ſhadow hether, Bleſt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Bleſt be the thing that brought the ſhadow hether, the ſhadow hether.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="19" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:27"/>
                     <head>XIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Ith bitter ſighs I heard <hi>Amintas</hi> play<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, For his chaſt loue, he found but deepe diſ╌daining, for <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> As thus he ſat, and in his griefe did tremble, To cheere his ſpirits the Aer'all queere aſ╌ſemble, aſ╌ſemble, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> They ſweetly ſing, they <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In dolefull tunes he cryes, Griefes are long liu'd, and ſorrow ſeldome dyes, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſel╌dome dyes, ſeldome dyes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="20" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:28"/>
                     <head>XX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doe I dying: Why doe I doubt to dye, to dye, and ſee death onely left me? left me, and ſee death onely left me, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> death <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Th'enlargement of my better ſelfe by natures foe, Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fines my hapleſſe life, to neuer dying woe, Immur'd in ſorrowes hold in ſorrowes hold, I onely ſee the light, ſee the light of all my ioyes, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Wrapt vp in horrors blackeſt night, blackeſt night, wrapt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then like Meander Swans, before my death, in fatall notes, In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In fatall notes, Ile ſigh my lateſt breath. ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my lateſt breath.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="21" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:28"/>
                     <head>XXI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N depth: And ſor╌row great, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Oft haue I, oft haue I, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oft haue I, my ſelfe bewayled, my <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Of that ſame loue, Of that ſame loue, that late had ſeat in my heart, my heart, in my heart, but now is failed, And ſorrow thou haſt done the worſt, That thou canſt doe to make me curſt. to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> curſt. And ſorrow thou haſt done the worſt, haſt done the worſt, That thou canſt doe to make me curſt. That thou canſt doe to make me curſt. That thou canſt doe to make me curſt.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="22" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:29"/>
                     <head>XXII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Ll the day I waſt in weeping, grieued with my loues diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>day╌ning, (Oh) grieued with my loues diſdaining, grieued <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> All the night I lye complaining, ſighes and ſobs, ſighes and ſobs me watchfull keeping, For thy loſſe, my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, But now too cruell, once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cru╌ell, once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> For thy loſſe my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, but now too cru╌ell. once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cru╌ell, once. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="23" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:29" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </head>
                     <opener>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doeſt thou? Stay or I dye, ſtay <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with endleſſe paine, Pittie, pittie, pittie, my plaint, alas, I faint, vnhappy me, wilt neuer be? wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and ſee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> thy wretched louer dye. Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee thy, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="24" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:30" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ome ſorrow, helpe me to lament, For plaining now muſt eaſe my heart, muſt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> No pleaſure can giue me content, For all delights doth breede my ſmart, my ſmart, for <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Onely my loue, my loue, can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe. all my griefe, all my griefe, whoſe abſence <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe, whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cauſeth all my griefe, all my griefe, Onely my loue, my loue, can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe, all my griefe, all my griefe, whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cauſeth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe.</p>
                     <trailer>Here endeth the Songs of fiue Parts.</trailer>
                  </div>
                  <div n="25" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:30" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Firſt part. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>
                           <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pid</hi> in a bed of Roſes, ſleep╌ing, Sleep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, chanced to be ſtung, of a Bee that lay among the flowers, a╌mong the flowers, Where he himſelfe repoſes, Where <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> repoſes, And thus to his mother weeping told, weeping told, That he this wound did take, did take, Of a little winged ſnake. As he lay ſecurely ſleep╌ing, ſleeping, ſleeping, And thus to his mother weeping told, weeping told, That he this wound did take, did take, of a little winged ſnake, As he lay ſecurely ſleep╌ing, ſleeping, ſleeping.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="26" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:31" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XXVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second part. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ythe╌rea</hi> ſmi╌ling ſaid, ſmiling ſaid, That if ſo great ſorrow ſpring, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> From a ſil╌ly Bees weake ſting, From <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> as ſhould make thee thus diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maid, as <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> What anguiſh feele they thinkſt thou, and what paine, Whom thy empoyſ'ned arrows cauſe complaine? whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cauſe complaine, complaine? What anguiſh feele they think'ſt thou, and what paine, Whom thy empoyſ'ned arrowes cauſe complaine? Whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cauſe complaine, complaine?</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="27" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:31" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>
                        <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Er haire, the net of goul╌den wire, Wherin my heart my heart, Led by my wandring eye, led by <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> led <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So faſt entangled is, entang╌led is, That in no wiſe it can or will a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaine re╌tire, againe retire it <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> againe retire, But rather will in that ſweet bondage dye, Then breake one haire to gaine her liber╌ty. her <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> her liberty. But ra╌ther will in that ſweet bondage dye, Then breake one haire, to gaine her liber╌ty her <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> then her <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="28" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:32" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XXVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 words">
                           <desc>〈◊◊〉</desc>
                        </gap> TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Ond loue is blind, Blinde therefore louers be, Blinde <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But I more blinde, more blinde, Who neare my loue did ſee, my <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my loue did ſee, <hi>Pigmal'on</hi> lou'd an Image, I a name, a name, I laught at him, But now de╌ſerue like blame, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus fooliſhly I leape before I looke, Seeing no baite I ſwallowed haue the hooke, Seeing no baite, I ſwallow'd haue the hooke. Thus fooliſhly I leape be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I looke, Seeing no baite, I ſwallowed haue the hooke. Seeing <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the hooke.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="29" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:32" rendition="simple:additions"/>
                     <head>XXIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second part. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg> Ah <hi>Cupid,</hi> grant that I╌may neuer ſee, Her through mine care, that thus hath wounded me, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> If through mine eyes another wound ſhe giue, <hi>Cupid</hi> alas, <hi>Cupid</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>las, then I no longer liue, <hi>Cupid</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharp arrowes, She ſtole from thy quiuer. She ſtole from thy qui╌uer. She ſtole from thy qui╌uer. But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharpe arrowes, She ſtole from thy quiuer. She ſtole from thy qui╌uer. She ſtole from thy qui╌uer.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="30" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:33"/>
                     <head>XXX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. TENOR.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>He with a cruell frowne, a <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oppreſt my trembling heart with deadly ſwone, with deadly ſwone, with dead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſwone, Yet pitt'ing my paine, yet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Reſtor'd with a kiſſe my life, my life againe, my life againe, againe, Reſtor'd with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe my life a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaine, Thus let me daily be of life depriued, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So I be daily thus againe reui╌ued. So I be daily thus againe reui╌ued, reui╌ued, So <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus let me daily be of life depriued, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So I be daily thus againe reui╌ued, ſo <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> reui╌ued, ſo <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſo <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <front>
               <gap reason="missing" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page missing〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <div type="illustration">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:34"/>
                  <p>
                     <figure>
                        <figDesc>coat of arms of Arthur, Lord Chichester, Baron of Belfast</figDesc>
                        <head>HONOR SEQVITVR FVGIENTEM</head>
                     </figure>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="dedication">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:34"/>
                  <head>TO THE RIGHT HONO<hi rend="sup">rable,</hi> 
                     <hi>ARTHVRE</hi> Lord <hi>CHICHESTER,</hi> Baron of BELFAST, Lord high Treaſurer of <hi>Jreland,</hi> and one of his Majeſties moſt Honorable Priuy Counſell, of that KINGDOME.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Right Honorable:</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">B</seg>Eing to expoſe theſe my vnworthy Labours to publicke view, and vniuerſall cenſure, I was imboldened in a double reſpect to become ſo humbly-ambitious, as to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire that they may take ſanctuary vnder your Honors all pleaſing name and ſafeſt patronage; Firſt, becauſe they were ſolely entended for your Honors priuate re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creation, after your tedious imployments in the af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fayres of the common-wealth, being then his Maieſties moſt worthy Deputy, and ſwaying the ſword and ſcep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of authority amongſt vs, in this kingdome of <hi>Ireland;</hi> And as your Honour hath beene pleaſed to vouchſafe vnto them your priuate applauſe, and thereby to occaſion me for more variety to enlarge them to this number: So I am bolde to father them vpon your Honor, not doubting but as in your allowance of them, I made vſe of your goodneſſe; ſo in your protection of them, I may make vſe of your greatneſſe. Secondly, it is not the leaſt of your Honors fauours conferred vpon me, to grace me with your Honourable ſeruice, and to call me to a more immediate dependency vpon your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, and therefore to auoide the blacke note of ingratitude, I held it my duty there to lay downe my worke, where I owe my ſeruice, and to deſire to be no longer knowne, then I may be knowne with that relation I haue to your Honour; that ſo I might leaue a perpetuall teſtimony vnto the world of your Honours fauours vnto mee; of my affectionate deſire, in ſome weake meaſure, to expreſſe my thankefulneſſe to your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour. If I haue herein giuen content to theſe curious and hard-pleaſed times, the thankes belongs to your Honour, whoſe encouragements were my motiues with gree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dineſſe to vndertake this taske, with conſtancy to goe through it, with reſolution to publiſh it, to the cenſorious eare of the world. If I haue come ſhort of popular expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, my hope is, that my mention of your Honorable name will procure pardon for a greater offence. And thus wiſhing vnto your Honor a continuall Harmony, compoſed of a comfortable delight of body, goods, and good name, with a daily increaſe of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, I humbly take leaue, crauing pardon for this boldneſſe, and deſiring alwaies to be accounted</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your Honours to be commanded in the beſt of his ſeruices THOMAS BATESON.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
               <div type="table_of_contents">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:35"/>
                  <head>THE TABLE.</head>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>3.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LOue is the fire that burnes me. I</item>
                     <item>My Miſtris after ſeruice due. II</item>
                     <item>One woman ſcarce of twenty. III</item>
                     <item>If I ſeeke to inioy. IIII</item>
                     <item>Pleaſure is a wanton thing. V</item>
                     <item>Sweet, thoſe trammels of your haire. VI</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>4.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LIue not poore bloome. VII</item>
                     <item>The Nightingale in ſilent night. VIII</item>
                     <item>Oh, what is ſhe? IX</item>
                     <item>See, ſee, forth her eyes her. X</item>
                     <item>When to the gloomy woods. XI</item>
                     <item>If floods of teares. XII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>5.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>HAue I found her? XIII</item>
                     <item>Downe the hills. XIIII</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Camella</hi> faire tript. XV</item>
                     <item>Sadneſſe ſit downe. XVI</item>
                     <item>Life of my life. XVII</item>
                     <item>I heard a noiſe. XVIII</item>
                     <item>With bitter ſighes. XIX</item>
                     <item>Why doe I dying liue? XX</item>
                     <item>In depth of greife. XXI</item>
                     <item>All the day, I waſt in weeping. XXII</item>
                     <item>Why doeſt thou flye? XXIII</item>
                     <item>Come ſorrow. XXIIII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>6.</hi> Voices.</head>
                     <item>
                        <hi>CVpid</hi> in a bed of Roſes. XXV</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Cytherea</hi> ſmiling ſaid. XXVI</item>
                     <item>Her haire, the net of. XXVII</item>
                     <item>Fond loue is blinde. XXVIII</item>
                     <item>Ah <hi>Cupid</hi> grant that I. XXIX</item>
                     <item>She with a cruell frowne, XXX</item>
                  </list>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </front>
            <body>
               <div n="bass" type="partbook">
                  <div n="1" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:35"/>
                     <head>I.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">L</seg>Oue is the fire that burnes me, loue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> The <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> The ſmokes are thoughts confuſed, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Which dimmes my ſoule, which dimmes, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And hath my ſence a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>buſed, Though fire to aſhes turnie me, Yet doth the ſmoke more grieue me, That dimmes my minde, Whoſe light ſhould ſtill relieue me, whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Though fire to aſhes turne me. Yet doth the ſmoake more grieue me, That dims my minde, whoſe light ſhould ſtill re╌lieue me. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="2" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:36"/>
                     <head>II.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">M</seg>Y Miſtriſſe after ſeruice due, Demaunded if indeed my loue were true, were true, I ſaid it was, Then ſhee replide, That I muſt hate whom ſhe de╌fide, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> de╌fide, And ſo my ſelfe, and ſo my ſelfe, aboue the reſt, aboue the reſt, Whom ſhe, ſhe ſwore, did moſt of all de╌teſt, whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In ſooth ſaid I, you ſee I hate my ſelfe, you <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Who ſets my loue on ſuch a pecuiſh elfe. who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Who ſets <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In ſooth ſaid I, you ſee I hate my ſelfe, you <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> who ſets my loue on ſuch a peeuiſh elfe. who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Who ſets my loue on ſuch a peeuiſh elfe.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="3" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:36"/>
                     <head>III.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>ONe woman ſcarce of twenty, But hath of teares great plenty, Which they powre out like fountaines, That runne downe from the mountaines, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Yet all is but beguiling, Their teares and eke their ſmi╌ling, their <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile therefore neuer truſt them, Since Nature hath ſo curſt them, ſince <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſo curſt them, That they can weepe in ſmiling, Poore fooles thereby begui╌ling. poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile therefore neuer truſt them, Since Nature hath ſo curſt them, ſince <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſo curſt them, That they can weepe in ſmiling, Poore fooles thereby begui╌ling. poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> poore <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="4" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:37"/>
                     <head>IIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>IF I ſeeke, If I ſeeke to inioy the fruits of my paine, She careles denyes me. She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with endles diſdaine, Yet ſo much I loue her, that nothing can either re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>moue me, or moue her, Alas, why contend I, why ſtriue I in vaine, The water to min<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gle, With Oyle that is Ayre, and loues to be ſingle, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Tis not loue but Fate whoſe doome I abide, You pow'rs and you plannets, which Deſte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies guide, Change your Oppoſition, Change <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> It fits heau'nly powers to be milde of condition. of condition. to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dition. condition. Change your Oppoſition, Change <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> It fits heau'nly powers to be milde of condi╌tion, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> condi╌ti╌on. condi╌tion.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="5" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:37"/>
                     <head>V.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">P</seg>Leaſure, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> is a wanton thing, When old and young doe dance and ſpring, doe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pleaſure, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> is a wanton thing, When old and young, when <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and young doe dance and ſpring, doe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pleaſure <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pleaſure it is that moſt deſire, And yet tis but a fooles hire. tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> a fooles hire. Pleaſure it is that moſt de╌ſire, And yet tis but a fooles hire. tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tis <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> a fooles hire.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="6" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:38"/>
                     <head>VI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 3. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Weet, thoſe Trammels of your haire, Golden locks more truely are, My thoughts locking to thy beautie, Thus you doe thus you doe, thus <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my captiue minde, From my dy ╌ing bo╌dy binde, Onely to you, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to doe duty. O my deere let it goe free, goe free, Or my body take to thee, take to thee, Or <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to thee, So your Captiue you ſhall cheriſh, you <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> For if parted thus they lye, they lye, Or my thoughts or I muſt dye, muſt dye, Or <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Or <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> T'will grieue thee, t'will grieue thee, if either pe╌riſh. if either pe╌riſh. pe╌riſh.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="7" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:38"/>
                     <head>VII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">L</seg>Iue not poore bloome, but periſh, Whoſe Spring fro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſty Winter blaſteth, Other buds freſh Mayes doe cheriſh, Hyems o're thee his ſnow ca╌ſteth, And in wither'd armes thee graſpeth, thee graſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peth, Tyrants, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> nothing worſe you can, nothing <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> you can, Now my liuely body's yoaked, my liuely, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to the dead corps of a man, of a man, Thus with loathed burden choked, Lingering death with teares inuoked Lingering <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="8" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:39"/>
                     <head>VIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>He Nightingale in ſilent night, Doth ſing as well as in the light, the light, doth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> doth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the light, To lull loues watchfull eyes aſleepe, She doth ſuch nightly ſonnets keepe, She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Hey hoe, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Sing we with all, What fortune vs ſo ere befall. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> befall. what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Hey hoe, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Sing we with all, What fortune vs ſo ere be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fall. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> befall. What fortune vs ſo ere befall.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="9" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:39"/>
                     <head>IX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. Firſt part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">O</seg>H, Oh what is ſhe, what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> what <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whoſe lookes like light╌nings pierce thus ſuddenly my breſt, thus <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Scorching no skinne? But oh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> but oh, my heart burnes with a fire fierce, The flames aſcending, the flames aſcending, aſcending, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> in my face are ſeene, in <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Yet courage man, Her ſpeaking eye doth ſhew, Some fire remaines, Some fire remaines, from whence thoſe light<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nings flew.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="10" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:40"/>
                     <head>X.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. Second part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Ee, ſee, ſee, ſee, ſee forth her eyes her ſtartled ſpirit peepes, Which now ſhe on me, which <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> which <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſtraight ſhe off me keepes, ſtraight ſhe off me keepes, Not able long, looks off, looks on, doth bluſh, doth tremble, Sweet wretch ſhe would, but can╌not loue diſſemble, ſweet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſweet <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Happy euent, Whats lingering is but ſleight is <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> is but ſleight, Who euer lou'd that lou'd not at firſt ſight? who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="11" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:40"/>
                     <head>XI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hen to the gloomy woods, When to the barren plains, When to the ſto╌ny rocks and ſullen floods, I wayling often goe, and of my Loue complaine, How ſenceles then thinke I, how <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> by loue I grow, To ſenceleſſe things that tell my woe? that tell my woe? Yet theſe my piercing moanes, my piercing mones haue touched oft ſo nye, haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oft ſo nye, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That they to me replie, to me reply, reply, But cruell, cruell, cruell ſhe, More ſenceles then hard ſtones, Quite ſenceles of my paines, No anſwer giues, no <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Vnmoued ſtill remaines. Vnmoued ſtill remaines. Vnmoued ſtill remaines.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="12" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:41"/>
                     <head>XII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 4. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>F floods of teares.</p>
                     <trailer>Here endeth the Songs of foure Parts.</trailer>
                  </div>
                  <div n="13" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:41"/>
                     <head>XIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Aue I found her? haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> (O rich finding) Goddeſſe like for to behold, for to behold, Her faire treſſes ſeemely binding, In a Chaine of pearle and gould, in <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In a Chaine of pearle and gould, of pearle and gould, Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me, O moſt faire, Chaine me to thee with that haire, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with that haire. Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me O moſt faire, Chaine me to thee with that haire, Chaine <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with that haire.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="14" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:42"/>
                     <head>XIIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>DOwne the hills <hi>Corina</hi> trips, <hi>Corina</hi> trips. Fetching many wanton ſkips, To the groues ſhe doth goe, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Where thouſand birds in a rowe, Sitting all vp╌on a tree, a tree, And three by three, <hi>Corina</hi> coueting to ſee, to ſee, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, to ſee, Tuning notes of her praiſe, Tuning <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with roun╌delayes. with roundelayes. with roun╌delayes. with roundelayes, with roun╌delayes. with rounde roundelayes. Tuning notes of her praiſe, tuning <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with roun╌delayes, with roundelayes. with roun╌delayes. with roundelayes. with roun╌delayes, with rounde roundelayes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="15" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:42"/>
                     <head>XV.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Amella</hi> faire tript or'e the plaine, tript <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tript <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I follow'd quickly after, Haue ouertaken her, haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I would faine, and kiſt her when I caught her, and kiſt her when I caught her, and kiſt her, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I caught her. But hope be'ng paſt her to obtaine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, She anſwerd me with great diſdaine, I will not kiſſe at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> not kiſſe at all. But hope be'ng paſt her to obtaine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, She anſwerd mee with great diſdaine, I will not kiſſe at all. I will not kiſſe at all. I will not kiſſe at all, at all. I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> not kiſſe at all.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="16" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:43"/>
                     <head>XVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Adneſſe ſit downe, ſit downe, on my ſoule feed, on my ſoule feede, Teare vp thoughts, tombe a numbed heart. tombe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tombe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> a numbed heart, Make wounds to ſpeake, and ſkarres to bleede, On withered ſtrings tune ſpringing ſmart, And leaue this farwell, for poſteritie, Life is a death where ſorrow cannot dye. Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> where ſorrow cannot dye. And leaue this farwell for poſteritie, Life is a death where ſorrow cannot dye. Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> where ſorrow cannot dye.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="17" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:43"/>
                     <head>XVII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">L</seg>Ife of my life: Or how ſhould I diſguiſe my ſecret ſmart, Wanting the ſweet fru'tion of thy face? Wanting the ſweet fru'tion of thy face? Where beauty, loue, with maieſtie and grace, Things ſeld or neuer, things <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> meeting in one place, Haue all conſpir'd to plague a plagued hart, all alwaies careles of my carefull caſe, Deere to my ſoule, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I pray thee make no ſtay, Goe not at all, or elſe with ſpeed returne, Nay rather far my deere goe not, goe not away, But thou muſt goe, Then ſweet while I thee ſee, Farwell, farwell, farwell, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But bide, or let me dye. but bide or let me dye. or let me dye.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="18" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:44"/>
                     <head>XVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg> Heard a noiſe, and wiſhed for a ſight, I lookt aſide, and did a ſhadow ſee, Whoſe ſubſtance was the ſum of my delight, It came vnſeene, and ſo it went from me, it went from me, But yet Conceit perſwaded my entent, There was a ſubſtance where the ſhadow went, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I did not play <hi>Narciſſus</hi> in conceit, I did not ſee my ſhadow in a ſpring, I knew my eyes were dim'd with no deceit, For as I ſaw the ſhadow paſsing by, I had a glance of ſomthing in my eye, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Shadow or ſhe, or both, or el uſe you whether, Bleſt be the thing that brought the ſhadow hether. Bleſt be the thing that brought the ſhadow hether.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="19" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:44"/>
                     <head>XIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Ith bitter ſighs I heard <hi>Amintas</hi> playning, For his chaſt loue, he found but deepe diſ╌daining, but deepe diſdaining, As thus he ſat, and in his griefe did tremble, To cheere his ſpirits the Aer'all queere aſſemble, aſſemble, They ſweetly ſing, they <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Griefes are long li'ud, and ſorrow ſeldome dyes. and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſorrow ſeldome dyes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="20" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:45"/>
                     <head>XX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doe I dying? Why doe I doubt to dye, and ſee death one╌ly left me? and ſee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> left me? and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Th'enlargement of my better ſelfe by natures foe, Confines my hapleſſe life to neuer dying woe, Immur'd in ſorrowes hold, in ſorrowes hold, I one<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly ſee the light, of all my ioyes, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Wrapt vp in horrors blackeſt night, wrapt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then like Meander Swans, before my death, in fatall notes Ile ſigh, in fa╌tall notes, in fatall notes, Ile ſigh my lateſt breath. Ile ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile ſigh my lateſt breath.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="21" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:45"/>
                     <head>XXI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N depth of griefe, And ſorrow great, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Oft haue I, oft haue I, oft haue I, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my ſelfe beway╌led, Of that ſame loue, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that late had ſeat in my heart, but now is failed, And ſorrow thou haſt done the worſt that thou canſt doe to make me curſt, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> me curſt, And ſorrow, thou haſt done the worſt, That thou canſt doe to make me curſt. that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> me curſt.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="22" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:46"/>
                     <head>XXII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. Firſt part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Ll the day, grieued with, grieued with my loues diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daining, All the night, ſighes and ſobs, ſighes and ſobs me watchfull keeping, For thy loſſe my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, but now too cru╌ell. once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> For thy loſſe, my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, But now too cru╌ell, once too kinde, But now too cruell.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="23" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:46"/>
                     <head>XXIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. Second Part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doeſt thou? Stay, or I dye with endleſſe paine, with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pittie, vnhappy me, wilt neuer be? wilt neuer be? Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="24" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:47"/>
                     <head>XXIIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ome ſorrow, helpe me to lament, For plaining now muſt eaſe my heart, my heart, No pleaſure can giue me content, For all delights doth breede my ſmart, doth breede my ſmart, Onely my loue, can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe. cauſeth all my griefe. my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe. my griefe. all my griefe, Onely my loue, can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe. cau<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſeth all my griefe. my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe. my griefe. all my griefe.</p>
                     <trailer>Here endeth the Songs of fiue Parts.</trailer>
                  </div>
                  <div n="25" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:47"/>
                     <head>XXV.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Firſt part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>
                           <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pid</hi> in a: Sleeping, ſleeping, chanced to be ſtung, of a Bee that lay among the flowers, a╌mong the flowers, Where he himſelfe repo╌ſes, Where he himſelfe repoſes, And thus to his mother weeping told, That he this wound did take, Of a little winged ſnake. As he lay ſecure ╌ly ſleeping. ſleep╌ing. And thus to his mother weeping told, That he this wound did take, of a little winged ſnake, As he lay ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>curely ſleeping. ſleep╌ing.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="26" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:48"/>
                     <head>XXVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second Part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ythe╌rea</hi> ſmi╌ling ſaid, ſmi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling ſaid, That if ſo great ſorrow ſpring, From a ſilly Bees weake ſting, From <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> as ſhould make thee thus diſmaid, What anguiſh feele they think'ſt thou, and what paine, Whom thy em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poyſ'ned arrowes cauſe complaine? Whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> What anguiſh feele they thinkſt thou, and what paine, Whom thy em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poyſoned arrowes cauſe complaine, whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whom thy em<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>poyſ'ned arrowes cauſe complaine?</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="27" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:48"/>
                     <head>XXVII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Er haire, the net of goulden wire, Wherin my heart, my heart, Led by my wandring eyes, So faſt entangled is, entangled is, entangled is, That in no wiſe it can, nor will againe retire, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tire, It <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> againe re╌tire, But rather will in that ſweet bondage die, Then breake one haire to gaine her liber╌ty. then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> her <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But rather will in that ſweet bondage dye, Then breake one haire, to gaine her liber╌ty. Then breake one haire to gaine her liberty, her liber╌ty.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="28" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:49"/>
                     <head>XXVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Firſt part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Ond loue. But I more blinde, Who neare my loue did ſee, my loue did ſee, who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> did ſee, <hi>Pigmal'on</hi> lou'd an Image, I an name, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I laught at him. But now deſerue like blame, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus fooliſhly I leap before I looke, Seeing no baite I ſwallow'd haue the hooke. I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus fooliſhly I leape before I looke, Seeing no baite, I ſwallow'd haue the hooke. I ſwallow'd haue the hooke.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="29" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:49"/>
                     <head>XXIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second part. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>H <hi>Cupid,</hi> grant that I may neuer ſee, Her through mine eare, that thus hath wounded me, wounded me, If through mine eyes another wound ſhe giue, <hi>Cu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pid</hi> a╌las, then I no lon╌ger liue, then I no longer liue, But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharpe arrowes, She ſtole from thy quiuer. She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharpe arrowes, She ſtole from thy quiuer. She ſtole from thy quiuer.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="30" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:50"/>
                     <head>XXX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. BASSVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>He with a cruell frowne, oppreſt my trembling heart with deadly ſwone, Yet pitt'ing my paine, Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtor'd with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe, my life againe, Re╌ſtor'd with a kiſſe my life, againe, Thus let me daily be of life depriued, So I be daily thus a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaine reuiued. ſo I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> reuiued, Thus let me daily be of life depriued, So I be daily thus againe reuiued. So I be daily thus againe reuiued. reuiued.</p>
                  </div>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
         <text xml:lang="eng">
            <front>
               <div type="title_page">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:51"/>
                  <p>QVINTVS.</p>
                  <p>THE SECOND SET <hi>OF</hi> MADRIGALES to 3. 4. 5. and 6. Parts: Apt for Viols and Voyces.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>NEWLY COMPOSED</hi> by Thomas Bateſon, Bacheler of MVSICKE, Organiſt, and Maſter of the Children of the Cathedrall Church <hi>of the bleſſed</hi> TRINITIE, <hi>Dublin, in</hi> the Realme of IRELAND.</p>
                  <p>
                     <hi>LONDON:</hi> Printed by <hi>Thomas Snodham,</hi> for <hi>Matthew Lownes</hi> and <hi>Iohn Browne.</hi> 1618.</p>
                  <floatingText type="license" xml:lang="eng">
                     <body>
                        <p>
                           <hi>Cum Priuilegio.</hi>
                        </p>
                     </body>
                  </floatingText>
               </div>
               <div type="illustration">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:52"/>
                  <p>
                     <figure>
                        <figDesc>coat of arms of Arthur, Lord Chichester, Baron of Belfast</figDesc>
                        <head>HONOR SEQVITVR FVGIENTEM</head>
                     </figure>
                  </p>
               </div>
               <div type="dedication">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:52"/>
                  <head>TO THE RIGHT HONO<hi rend="sup">rable,</hi> 
                     <hi>ARTHVRE</hi> Lord <hi>CHICHESTER,</hi> Baron of BELFAST, Lord high Treaſurer of <hi>Jreland,</hi> and one of his Majeſties moſt Honorable Priuy Counſell, of that KINGDOME.</head>
                  <opener>
                     <salute>Right Honorable:</salute>
                  </opener>
                  <p>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">B</seg>Eing to expoſe theſe my vnworthy Labours to publicke view, and vniuerſall cenſure, I was imboldened in a double reſpect to become ſo humbly-ambitious, as to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire that they may take ſanctuary vnder your Honors all-pleaſing name and ſafeſt patronage; Firſt, becauſe they were ſolely entended for your Honors priuate re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creation, after your tedious imployments in the af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fayres of the common-wealth, being then his Maieſties moſt worthy Deputy, and ſwaying the ſword and ſcep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter of authority amongſt vs, in this kingdome of <hi>Ireland;</hi> And as your Honour hath beene pleaſed to vouchſafe vnto them your priuate applauſe, and thereby to occaſion me for more variety to enlarge them to this number: So I am bolde to father them vpon your Honor, not doubting but as in your allowance of them, I made vſe of your goodneſſe; ſo in your protection of them, I may make vſe of your greatneſſe. Secondly, it is not the leaſt of your Honors fauours conferred vpon me, to grace me with your Honourable ſeruice, and to call me to a more immediate dependency vpon your Lord<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhip, and therefore to auoide the blacke note of ingratitude, I held it my duty there to lay downe my worke, where I owe my ſeruice, and to deſire to be no longer knowne, then I may be knowne with that relation I haue to your Honour; that ſo I might leaue a perpetuall teſtimony vnto the world of your Honours fauours vnto mee; of my affectionate deſire, in ſome weake meaſure, to expreſſe my thankefulneſſe to your Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour. If I haue herein giuen content to theſe curious and hard-pleaſed times, the thankes belongs to your Honour, whoſe encouragements were my motiues with gree<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dineſſe to vndertake this taske, with conſtancy to goe through it, with reſolution to publiſh it, to the cenſorious eare of the world. If I haue come ſhort of popular expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, my hope is, that my mention of your Honorable name will procure pardon for a greater offence. And thus wiſhing vnto your Honor a continuall Harmony, compoſed of a comfortable delight of body, goods, and good name, with a daily increaſe of Ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour, I humbly take leaue, crauing pardon for this boldneſſe, and deſiring alwaies to be accounted</p>
                  <closer>
                     <signed>Your Honours to be commanded in the beſt of his ſeruices THOMAS BATESON.</signed>
                  </closer>
               </div>
               <div type="table_of_contents">
                  <pb facs="tcp:150784:53"/>
                  <head>THE TABLE.</head>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>3.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LOue is the fire that burnes me. II</item>
                     <item>My Miſtris after ſeruice due. II</item>
                     <item>One woman ſcarce of twenty. III</item>
                     <item>If I ſeeke to inioy. IIII</item>
                     <item>Pleaſure is a wanton thing. V</item>
                     <item>Sweet, thoſe trammels of your haire. VI</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>4.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>LIue not poore bloome. VII</item>
                     <item>The Nightingale in ſilent night. VIII</item>
                     <item>Oh, what is ſhe? IX</item>
                     <item>See, ſee, forth her eyes her. X</item>
                     <item>When to the gloomy woods. XI</item>
                     <item>If floods of teares. XII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>5.</hi> Voyces.</head>
                     <item>HAue I found her? XIII</item>
                     <item>Downe the hills. XIIII</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Camella</hi> faire tript. XV</item>
                     <item>Sadneſſe ſit downe. XVI</item>
                     <item>Life of my life. XVII</item>
                     <item>I heard a noiſe. XVIII</item>
                     <item>With bitter ſighes. XIX</item>
                     <item>Why doe I dying liue? XX</item>
                     <item>In depth of greife. XXI</item>
                     <item>All the day, I waſt in weeping. XXII</item>
                     <item>Why doeſt thou flye? XXIII</item>
                     <item>Come ſorrow. XXIIII</item>
                  </list>
                  <list>
                     <head>Songs of <hi>6.</hi> Voices.</head>
                     <item>
                        <hi>CVpid</hi> in a bed of Roſes. XXV</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Cytherea</hi> ſmiling ſaid. XXVI</item>
                     <item>Her haire, the net of. XXVII</item>
                     <item>Fond loue is blinde. XXVIII</item>
                     <item>Ah <hi>Cupid</hi> grant that I. XXIX</item>
                     <item>She with a cruell frowne, XXX</item>
                  </list>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </front>
            <body>
               <div n="quintus" type="partbook">
                  <div n="13" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:53"/>
                     <head>XIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Aue I found her? haue <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> O rich finding, Goddeſſe like for to behold, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Her faire treſſes ſeemely bind╌ing, In a chaine of pearle and gould, In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me O moſt faire, O moſt faire, Chaine me to thee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me to thee with that haire. <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with that haire. Chaine me, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me, O moſt faire, O moſt faire, Chaine me to thee <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Chaine me to thee with that haire, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with that haire.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="14" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:54"/>
                     <head>XIIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>DOwne the hills <hi>Corina</hi> trips, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <hi>Co╌rina</hi> trips, Fetching many wanton ſkips, To the groues ſhe doth goe, ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſhe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Where thouſand birds in a rowe, Sitting all vp╌on a tree, Came two by two, And three by three, and and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <hi>Corina</hi> coueting to ſee, to ſee <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> to ſee, <hi>Corina</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <hi>Corina</hi> to ſee, Tuning notes of her praiſe, Tuning <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of her praiſe, Doth welcome her with rounde roundelayes. with roun╌delayes. with rounde roundelayes. with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with roun╌delayes, roundelayes. Tuning notes of her praiſe, tuning <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of her praiſe, Doe welcome her with rounde roundelayes. with roun╌delayes. with rounde roundelayes. with rounde╌roundelayes, with roun╌delayes. roundelayes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="15" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:54"/>
                     <head>XV.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Amella</hi> faire tript or'e the plaine, <hi>Camella</hi> 
                        <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> tript <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I follow'd quickly after, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> quickly after, Haue ouertaken her, I would faine, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and kiſt her when I caught her, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I caught her, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But hope be'ng paſt her to obtaine, to obtaine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, She anſwerd me with great diſdaine, I wil not kiſſe at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe at all, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I wil not kiſſe at all. But hope be'ng paſt her to obtaine, to obtaine, <hi>Camella</hi> loud I call, She anſwerd me with great diſdaine, I will not kiſſe at all. I will not kiſſe at all, at all. I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> kiſſe at all, I will not, I will not kiſſe at all.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="16" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:55"/>
                     <head>XVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>Adneſſe ſit downe, ſit downe, on my ſoule feed, on <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> on my ſoule feede, Teare vp thoughts, tombe a numbed heart, tombe a num╌bed heart, tombe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Make wounds to ſpeake, and ſkarres to bleede, On withered ſtrings tune ſpringing ſmart, And leaue this farwell, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> for poſteritie, Life is a death, where ſorrow cannot dye. Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> not dye Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cannot dye. And leaue this farwell and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> for poſteritie, Life is a death, where ſorrow cannot dye. Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> not dye. Life <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cannot dye.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="17" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:55"/>
                     <head>XVII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>LIfe of my life, how ſhould I liue, alas, Since thou art thus re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſolu'd for to de╌part? Or how ſhould I, or how ſhould I diſguiſe my ſe╌cret ſmart, Wanting the ſweet fru'tion of thy face, Wanting the ſweet of thy face? Wher beauty, loue, with maieſtie and grace, with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and grace, Things ſeld or neuer, things <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> things <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> meeting in one place, Haue all conſpir'd to plague a plag╌ued hart, All alwaies careleſſe of my carefull caſe, Deere to my ſoule, Deere <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I pray thee make no ſtay, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Goe not at all, or els with ſpeed return, Nay rather far my deer goe not away, But thou muſt goe, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then ſweet while I thee ſee, Farwell, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> farwell, But bide or let me dye. me dye. but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> or let me dye.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="18" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:56"/>
                     <head>XVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>I Heard a noiſe, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and wiſhed for a ſight, I lookt aſide, and did a ſhadow ſee, Whoſe ſubſtance was the ſumme of my delight, the <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> It came vnſeene, and ſo it went from me, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But yet Conceit perſwaded my entent, There was a ſubſtance where the ſhadow went, where <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I did not play <hi>Narciſſus</hi> in conceit, <hi>Narciſſus</hi> in conceit, conceit, I did not ſee my ſhadow in a ſpring, a ſpring, I knew my eyes were dim'd with no de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceit, I ſaw the ſhadow of ſome worthy thing, For as I ſaw the ſhadow paſsing by, I had a glance of ſomthing in my eie, in my eie, my eie, Shadow or ſhe, or both, or chuſe you whether, Bleſt be the thing that brought the ſhadow hether, Bleſt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Bleſt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Bleſt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> the ſhadow hether.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="19" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:56"/>
                     <head>XIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Ith bitter ſighs I heard <hi>Amintas</hi> play╌ning, play<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, For his chaſt loue he found but deepe diſdai╌ning, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> As thus he ſat, as thus he ſat, and in his griefe did tremble, To cheere his ſpirits the Aer'all queere, the Aer'all queere aſſem╌ble, They ſweetly ſing, they <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In dolefull tunes he cryes, Griefes are long li'ud, long li'ud, and ſorrow ſeldome dyes, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> dyes, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dome dyes. and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> dyes.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="20" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:57"/>
                     <head>XX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doe I dying liue, and ſee my life bereft me? and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> bereft me? Why doe I doubt to dye, and ſee death onely left me? and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> left me, left me? Th'enlargement of my better ſelfe by natures foe, Confines my hapleſſe life, to neuer dying woe, Immur'd in ſorrowes hold, I onely ſee the light, the light of all my ioyes, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Wrapt vp in horrors blackeſt night, wrapt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then like Meander Swans, before my death, in fatall notes, In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> In <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile ſigh my lateſt breath. Ile ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile ſigh, Ile ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Ile ſigh, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my lateſt breath. Ile ſigh my lateſt breath.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="21" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:57"/>
                     <head>XXI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">I</seg>N depth of griefe, And ſorrow great, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> great, and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Oft haue I, oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oft <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my ſelfe beway╌led, beway╌led, Of that ſame loue, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that late had ſeat in my heart, in my heart, in my heart, my heart, but now is fai╌led, And ſorrow thou haſt done the worſt, haſt done the worſt, that thou canſt doe to make me curſt, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And ſorrow, thou haſt done the worſt, That thou canſt doe to make me curſt. to <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> me curſt.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="22" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:58"/>
                     <head>XXII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. Firſt part. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Ll the day, I waſt in wee╌ping, grieued with my loues, (O) grieued with my loues, (O) grieued with my loues diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>daining, my loues diſdaining, All the night I lye complaining, ſighes and ſobs, ſighes <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſighes and ſobs me watchfull keeping, For thy loſſe my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, but now too cru╌ell. once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ell, once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> For thy loſſe, my liues bright Iewell, Once too kinde, But now too cruell, once <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> cru╌ell, once too <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan>
                     </p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="23" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:58"/>
                     <head>XXIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. Second part. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>Hy doeſt thou flye in ſuch diſdaine? Stay or I dye, Oh ſtay or I dye with endleſſe paine, with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Pittie, pittie, alas, I faint, vnhappy me, wilt neuer be? wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> wilt <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Then yet at laſt glance backe thy eye, And ſee thy wretched louer dye. and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> and ſee thy <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> thy wretched louer dye.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="24" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:59"/>
                     <head>XXIIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 5. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ome ſorrow, helpe me to lament, For plaining now muſt eaſe my heart, for <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> No pleaſure can giue me content, For all delights doth breede my ſmart, doth breed my ſmart, doth <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Onely my loue can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe, whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my griefe. all my griefe. my griefe whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Onely my loue, can yeeld reliefe, Whoſe abſence cauſeth all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> all my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> my griefe. all my griefe. my griefe. whoſe <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> griefe.</p>
                     <trailer>Here endeth the Songs of fiue Parts.</trailer>
                  </div>
                  <div n="25" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:59"/>
                     <head>XXV.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Firſt part. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>
                           <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pid</hi> in a bed of Roſes, of roſes, of roſes Sleeping, ſleep╌ing, chanced to be ſtung, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of a Bee that lay among the flowers, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Where he himſelfe repoſes, Where <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And thus to his mother wee╌ping told, That he this wound did take, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Of a little winged ſnake. of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> As he lay ſecurely ſleeping, ſecurely ſleep╌ing, ſecurely ſleeping, As <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> And thus to his mother wee╌ping told, That he this wound did take, that <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> of a little winged ſnake, of <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> As he lay ſecurely ſleep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, ſecurely ſleep╌ing, ſecurely ſleeping, As he lay ſecurely ſleeping.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="26" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:60"/>
                     <head>XXVI.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second Part. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <hi>
                           <seg rend="decorInit">C</seg>Ythe╌rea</hi> ſmi╌ling ſaid, ſmiling ſaid, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> That if ſo great ſorrow ſpring, From a ſil╌ly Bees weake ſting, From <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> a ſilly <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> as ſhould make thee thus diſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maid, as ſhould make thee thus diſ╌maid, ſhould <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> What anguiſh feele they thinkſt thou and what paine, Whom thy empoyſ'ned arrows cauſe complaine? cauſe com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plaine, complaine? whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> What anguiſh feele they think'ſt thou, and what paine, Whom thy empoyſ'ned arrowes cauſe complaine? cauſe complaine, complaine? Whom <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Whom thy empoyſ'ned arrowes cauſe complaine?</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="27" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:60"/>
                     <head>XXVII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>Er haire, the net of goul╌den wire, Wherein my heart, my heart, Wherein my heart, my heart, wherein <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Led by my wandring eye, my <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Led by my wandring eye, So faſt entangled is, entangled is, That in no wiſe it can or will againe re╌tire, it <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> againe re╌tire, it can or will againe re╌tire, But ra╌ther will in that ſweet bondage dye, Then breake one haire to gaine her liber╌ty. Then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> her liberty. Then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But ra╌ther will in that ſweet bondage dye, Then breake one haire, to gaine her liber╌ty. Then <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> her liberty. Then breake one haire to gaine her libertie.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="28" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:61"/>
                     <head>XXVIII.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Ond loue is blind, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Blinde therefore louers be, <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But I more blinde, But I more blinde, Who neare my loue did ſee, Who <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> did ſee, did ſee, <hi>Pigmal'on</hi> lou'd an Image, I a name, I laught at him, I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> But now deſerue like blame, like blame, but now deſerue like blame, like blame, but <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus fooliſhly I leape before I looke, See╌ing no baite I ſwallow'd haue the hooke, Seeing <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus fooliſhly I leape be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore I looke, Seeing no baite, I ſwallow'd haue the hooke. Seeing <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> I ſwallow'd haue the hooke.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="29" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:61"/>
                     <head>XXIX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. Second part. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>H <hi>Cupid,</hi> grant that I may neuer ſee, Her through mine eare, that thus hath wounded me, her through my eare that thus hath wounded me If through mine eyes ano╌ther wound ſhe giue, another <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> 
                        <hi>Cupid</hi> a╌las, then I no longer liue, <hi>Cupid</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>las, then I no lon╌ger liue, But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharpe arrowes, She ſtole from thy quiuer. from thy quiuer, She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> She But dye poore wretch, Shot through and through the liuer, With thoſe ſharpe arrowes, ſhe ſtole from thy qui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uer. from thy quiuer. She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> She <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> ſhe ſtole from thy quiuer.</p>
                  </div>
                  <div n="30" type="madrigal">
                     <pb facs="tcp:150784:62"/>
                     <head>XXX.</head>
                     <opener>Of 6. Voc. QVINTVS.</opener>
                     <p>
                        <gap reason="music">
                           <desc>〈♫〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                        <seg rend="decorInit">S</seg>He with a cruell frowne, a <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> oppreſt my trembling heart with deadly ſwone, with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Yet pitt'ing my paine, Reſtor'd with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe, my life a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaine, reſtor'd <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> with a kiſſe, with a kiſſe, my life a╌gaine re╌ſtor'd with a kiſſe, my life againe, Thus let me daily be of life depri╌ued, So I be daily thus againe reui╌ued. ſo I be <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So I be <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So I be <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> Thus let me daily be of life depriued, So I be daily thus againe reui╌ued. So I be <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> So <expan>
                           <am>
                              <g ref="char:repeat"/>
                           </am>
                           <ex>repeat</ex>
                        </expan> reuiued.</p>
                  </div>
                  <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
               </div>
            </body>
         </text>
      </group>
   </text>
</TEI>
